Guide to the Ralph W. Tyler Papers 1932-1988
University of Chicago Library
- Series IV: Writings by Tyler
  - Subseries 2: Periodicals
    - 1975, "Remembering Boyd Bode." No. 1, 1975 "Where Learning Happens." January-February "Universal Education in the United States; Milestone Influences on the Past and Future." March "A View of the Past and to the Future." [National Assessment of Educational Progress.] June "Some Comments on Power and the NAEP." July-August "Tomorrow's Education." August-September "Reconstructing the Total Educational Environment." September "Educational Requirements for a Modern Democracy." October (Box 57, Folder 16)
    - 1976-1977, "Social Policy and Self-Help Groups." July-August-September "Two New Emphases in Curriculum Development." October "Education American Style." November-December "School and Character Development." January-February "What Technology Cannot Do." February "An Interview with Ralph Tyler." March "It's All a Matter of Learning." Summer "Fifty Years of Theory and Practice." September-October "Learning in America." November-December "Toward Improved Curriculum Theory; The Inside Story." No. 4, 1977 (Box 57, Folder 17)
    - 1978-1979, "Unfinished Tasks of American Education." Spring "Some Observations on Chinese Education." September "Technological Horizons in Education; An Overview." September-October Comments and interview in "Conflicting Views on Competency Testing in Florida." November "The Role of State Educational Agencies in the Area of Educational Research." Winter "The Wingspread Papers; A Report on the Minimum Competency Movement." January "Comments on `Science Education in the People's Republic of China; Observations and Impressions.'" April "Comparing American Schools with Schools in Other Nations." April (Box 57, Folder 18)
    - 1980, "High School Goals; Responses to John Henry Martin." January "Utilization of Technological Media, Devices, and Systems in the Schools." January "Landmarks in the Literature; What Was Learned from the Eight-Year Study?" Winter 1980 "Why Research Is Needed in Education." Winter "Stimulating an Informed in Education." Winter "Stimulating an Informed Dialogue on Important Educational Issues." April "A Brief Overview of Program Evaluation." Summer "Teachers and Teaching in the 1980s." Summer "Curriculum Issues; Retrospect and Prospect." Fall "On Educational Policies." October (Box 57, Folder 19)
    - 1981, "The U.S. vs. the World; A Comparison of Educational Performance." January "How We Got Where We Are." [Qualitative evaluation.] Winter "Curriculum Development Since 1900." May "The Values of Cooperative Education from a Pedagogical Perspective." Summer "Needed Research on the Education of Older Adults." September "Reflections on Independent Individualized Instruction." September "Minimum Competency Testing Is Reducing Attention to the Social Studies." Fall Review of Educational and Psychological Measurement and Evaluation. November (Box 57, Folder 20)
    - 1982-1983, "Dynamic Response in a Time of Decline." June "Comment by Ralph Tyler." [National Assessment of Educational Progress.] December "Education for Participation; Implications for School Curriculum and Instruction." Nos. 3/4, 1982 "A Place Called School." March "The Contribution of `A Study of Schooling' to Educational Research." April "On Educational Evaluation; A Conversation with Ralph Tyler." May "Educational Assessment, Standards, and Quality; Can We Have One Without the Others?" Summer "Tyler Talks." Summer "Some Thoughts on the Improvement of American Public Education." August "Using Technology to Improve Education." Fall (Box 57, Folder 21)
    - 1984-1985, "Personal Reflections on `The Practical 4' [by Joseph Schwab]." Spring "A Guide to Educational Trouble-Shooting." May [Comment on definition and control of educational content by states.] April "What We've Learned from Past Studies of Teacher Education." June "Interviews with Ralph W. Tyler." Fall (Box 57, Folder 22)
    - 1986, "Changing Concepts of Educational Evaluation." No. 1, 1986 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - 1986, "Ralph W. Tyler; Special Topic Edition." Spring (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - 1986, "Continuing the Quest for Excellence." Spring "Testing Teachers and Prospective Teachers." Summer "David Cohen Talks with Ralph Tyler." No. 3, 1986 "Educating Supervisors for Schools in a Democratic Society." December "The Five Most Significant Curriculum Events in the Twentieth Century." December (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - 1987, "Charles Hubbard Judd; As I Came to Know Him." February "The Mission of Supervision in a Democratic Society." Spring "Attaining Quality Education." Summer "Examining the Current Demands for Curricular Reforms from a Historical Perspective." Summer Reviews of Curriculum and Aims and Curriculum; Perspective, Paradigm, and Possibility. Summer "Education Reforms." December (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 3: Books, Pamphlets, and Papers
    - 1930, Research Methods and Teachers' Problems; A Manual for Systematic Studies of Classroom Procedure (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - 1931, "The Development of Examinations at Ohio State University." In Recent Trends in American College Education "Ohio State University." In Practices of American Universities in Granting Higher Degrees in Education (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - 1931, What People Want to Read About; A Study of Group Interests and a Survey of Problems in Adult Reading (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - 1932, "Certain Administrative Procedures in Botany and Zoology." In Service Studies in Higher Education "Construction of Examinations in Botany and Zoology." In Service Studies in Higher Education "A Survey of Present Training Courses for Research Workers." In Proceedings of the Seventieth Annual Meeting of the National Education Association (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - 1934, Constructing Achievement Tests (Box 58, Folder 9)
    - 1934, "Cooperation of Teachers of Liberal Arts with Teachers of Education." In Abstracts of Papers at the Cleveland Meeting "Discussion of a Theory of Selection of College Students." In Transactions of the Sixty-second and Sixty-third Annual Meetings of the Ohio College Association "Measuring the Effectiveness of Instruction." In Proceedings of the Forty-seventh Annual Convention of the Association of Land-Grant Colleges and Universities (Box 58, Folder 10)
    - 1935, "Characteristics of a Satisfactory Diagnosis." In Educational Diagnosis "Elements of Diagnosis." In Educational Diagnosis "Techniques for Evaluating Behavior." In Educational Responsibilities of Today and Tomorrow (Box 58, Folder 11)
    - 1936, "Evaluating the Outcomes of The Social Studies Curriculum." In The Social Studies Curriculum "Identification and Definition of the Objectives to Be Measured." In The Construction and Use of Achievement Examinations "Methods Used in Improving Tests and Examinations at the Ohio State University." In Tests and Measurements in Higher Education "Needed Research in the Field of Tests and Examinations." In Tests and Measurements in Higher Education (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - 1936, "The Relation Between Recall and Higher Mental Processes." In Education as Cultivation of the Higher Mental Processes (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - 1936, "To What Degree Can the Content of the Social Studies Be Selected on an Objective Basis?" In Proceedings of the Seventy-fourth Annual Meeting of the National Education Association "Examinations in the Natural Sciences." In The Construction and Use of Achievement Examinations (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - 1937, "The Evaluation of Professional Training." In Sixteenth Yearbook [American Association of Teachers Colleges] "The Study of Adolescent Reading by the Progressive Education Association." In Library Trends (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - 1938, "Evaluating 4-H Club Work." In Proceedings; Seventeenth National 4-H Club Congress "The Specific Techniques of Investigation; Examining and Testing Acquired Knowledge, Skill, and Ability." In The Scientific Movement in Education (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - 1939, "Basic Assumptions Which Guide My Work in Educational Measurement." In Research on the Foundations of American Education "Co-operation in the Study of Institutional Problems." In The Outlook for Higher Education "Evaluation in Teacher Education Programs." In Bennington Planning Conference for the Cooperative Study of Teacher Education "Evaluation of Business-Education Criteria." In Business Education in School Situations "Training Administrative Officers for Democratic Leadership." In Democratic Practices in School Administration Summer Workshops in Secondary Education; An Experiment in the In-Service Training of Teachers and Other Educational Workers (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - 1940, "An Appraisal of Techniques of Evaluation; A Critique." In Official Report of the 1940 Meeting [American Educational Research Association] "The Future of the Liberal Arts College." In Thirty-sixth Annual Meeting of the Federation of Illinois Colleges "Newer Techniques in Evaluating Growth." In Reading and Pupil Development "The Place of Evaluation in Modern Education." In Evaluating the Work of the School School and College Regional Conference, Commission on the Relation of School and College of the Progressive Education Association What the High Schools Ought to Teach (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - 1941, "Contribution of Tests to Research in the Field of Student Personnel Work." In Report of the Eighteenth Annual Meeting of the American College Personnel Association "Educational Adjustments Necessitated by Changing Ideological Concepts." In Administrative Adjustments Required by Socio-Economic Change "Evaluation of Guidance." In Proceedings of the Sixth Annual Guidance Conference Held at Purdue University "The Interpretation of Evaluation Results." In Proceedings of the Workshop in General Education Introduction to and "Use of the Survey Report." In Survey of Hinsdale Schools "Principles Involved in Evaluating Student Personnel Services." In Student Personnel Services in Colleges and Universities "The Relation of the Curriculum to American Democratic Ideals." In Education in a Democracy Review of "Cooperative Biology Test." In The Nineteen Forty Mental Measurements Yearbook Review of "Cooperative Contemporary Affairs Test for College Students." In The Nineteen Forty Mental Measurements Yearbook "A Summary of Trends in the Attack on College Instructional Problems." In New Frontiers in Collegiate Instruction (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - 1942, "Cooperation in Teacher Education as Related to Our War Effort." In National Institutional Teacher Placement Association; Proceedings of the Ninth Annual Autumn Conference "Evaluation Must Be Continual and Flexible." In General Education in the American High School "Implications of Communications Research for the Public Schools." In Print, Radio, and Film in a Democracy "Purposes and Procedures of the Evaluation Staff." In Appraising and Recording Student Progress; Evaluation, Records and Reports in the Thirty Schools (Box 59, Folder 9)
    - 1942, "Putting Life Values into Science Education." In The Science Teacher Yearbook Supplement "Relations of the Urban Community and the Modern School." In The School and the Urban Community "Trends in the Preparation of Teachers." In Annual Report and Proceedings of the Forty-eighth Annual Convention of the National League of Nursing Education Foreword to Community Workshops for Teachers in the Michigan Community Health Project (Box 59, Folder 9)
    - 1943, "Acceptance of Military Experience Toward College Credit." In Higher Education Under War Conditions "Appraisal of Military Training and Experience." In Challenges to Education, War and Post-War "Eight-Year Study of the Progressive Education Association." In Encyclopedia of Modern Education "Evaluation as a Function of Supervision." In Challenges to Education, War and Post-War Foreword to and "Introduction to Subsequent Chapters." In Survey Report, Waukegan Township High School District 119 "Function of the Graduate School in the Education of Teachers." In Proceedings of the Association of Land-Grant Colleges and Universities Introduction to Survey of Elementary Schools, Highland Park, Illinois "The Role of the Schools in the Nation's War Efforts." In War and Post-War Responsibilities of American Schools "Summary of the Conference." In The Colleges in Wartime; New Responsibilities "Wartime Interests and Needs and Their Relation to Reading Programs." In Adapting Reading Programs to Wartime Needs "The School Curriculum." In Survey of Elementary Schools, Highland Park, Illinois Education for Freedom When Johnny Comes Marching Home (Box 59, Folder 10)
    - 1944, "Admission and Articulation Based on Study of the Individual." In New Directions for Measurement and Guidance "Responsibility of the School for the Improvement of American Life." In Significant Aspects of American Life and Postwar Education (Box 59, Folder 11)
    - 1945, Foreword to Summary of Survey Report, Battle Creek Public Schools Foreword to Survey of Public Schools, Battle Creek, Michigan Foreword to Survey Report, The Shattuck School, Faribault, Minnesota Introduction to American Education in the Postwar Period; Curriculum Reconstruction "What Rural Schools Can Learn from the Training Programs of the Armed Forces." In Education for Rural America "Workshop to Study Methods of Evaluating Extension Education." In Report of Workshop to Study Methods of Evaluating Extension Programs (Box 59, Folder 12)
    - 1946, "The Evaluation of Faculty Services." In Problems of Faculty Personnel "The Role of University Departments of Education in the Preparation of School Administrators." In Educational Administration; A Survey of Progress, Problems, and Needs "Situations Requiring an Extension of Institutional Responsibilities for Counseling and Guidance." In Emergent Responsibilities in Higher Education "Summary of Criteria for Appraising a School's Reading Program." In The Appraisal of Current Practices in Reading "What Is Supervision?" In North Central States Extension Supervision Workshop Report G.I. Education Education and the G.I.'s (Box 59, Folder 13)
    - 1947, "Discussion." [Aptitude testing.] In Third Congress on Dental Education and Licensure "Evaluation of Extension Supervision." In Western Regional Workshop for Extension Supervisors (Box 59, Folder 14)
    - 1947, Foreword to Cooperation in General Education; A Final Report of the Executive Committee of the Cooperative Study in General Education + Foreword in General Education in the Humanities, 1947; General Education in the Social Studies, 1948; and Student Personnel Services in General Education, 1949 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - 1947, "Proposals for Adults." In Administrative Planning for School Programs and Plants (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - 1948, "The Accomplishments and the Promise of Educational Research in Sharpening the Tools of Educational Science." In Improving Educational Research [Presentations on objectives, evaluation, extension program building.] In Report of Home Demonstration Leaders' Workshop "The School Curriculum in General." In Report of the Directed Self Survey, Winnipeg Public Schools "The Significance of This Investigation to School Administrators, to Teachers and to Students of Education." In How Well Are Indian Children Educated? Equality of Educational Opportunity (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - 1949, "Achievement Testing and Curriculum Construction." In Trends in Student Personnel Work "Educational Problems in Other Professions." In Education for Librarianship Preface to Adolescent Character and Personality Review of "Cooperative Test on Recent Social and Scientific Developments." In The Third Mental Measurements Yearbook "The School Curriculum in General." In Grand Rapids School Survey, Grand Rapids, Michigan What Should Society Expect from a University? (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - 1949, Basic Principles of Curriculum and Instruction (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - Basic Principles of Curriculum and Instruction, in Danish (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - Basic Principles of Curriculum and Instruction, in Dutch (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - Basic Principles of Curriculum and Instruction, in German (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - Basic Principles of Curriculum and Instruction, in Japanese (Box 60, Folder 9)
    - Basic Principles of Curriculum and Instruction, in Portuguese (Box 60, Folder 10)
    - Basic Principles of Curriculum and Instruction, in Spanish (Box 60, Folder 11)
    - Basic Principles of Curriculum and Instruction, Nigerian edition in English (Box 60, Folder 12)
    - [About]; "Significant Writings That Have Influenced the Curriculum; 1906-81" (Box 60, Folder 13)
    - 1950, "The Curriculum and Instruction" and "The Elementary Schools." In School Survey, Taylorville, Illinois, Community Unit District No. 3 "Discussion by Ralph W. Tyler." In A Forum on the Public Library Inquiry Basic Principles of Curriculum and Instruction. (University of Chicago Press, 1950) (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - 1950, "The Organization of Learning Experiences." In Toward Improved Curriculum Theory "Next Steps in the Development of a More Adequate Curriculum Theory." In Toward Improved Curriculum Theory (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - 1950, Foreword to Milwaukee-Downer College, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, Survey Report "Implications for Improving Instruction in the High School." In Learning and Instruction "The Committee on Relations with Higher Institutions." In New College Admission Requirements Recommended (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - 1951, "Can Intelligence Tests Be Used to Predict Educability?" In Intelligence and Cultural Differences "Evolving a Functional Curriculum." In Annual Report of the National League of Nursing Education "The Functions of Graduate Departments and Schools of Education." In Graduate Study in Education "The Functions of Measurement in Improving Instruction." In Educational Measurement "Graduate Programs in Education at the University of Chicago." In Graduate Study in Education Love Is Not Enough "Evaluation." In The Schools and National Security (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - 1952, "Distinctive Attributes of Education for the Professions." In Proceedings of the 1952 Annual Meeting, American Association of Schools of Social Work (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - 1953, "Clear Objectives in Supervision as a Means of Promoting Good Human Relations." In Knowledge and Skill in Working with Others "How Do People Learn?" In Increasing Understanding of Public Problems and Policies "Translating Youth Needs into Teaching Goals." In Adapting the Secondary-School Program to the Needs of Youth "What Research Shows About the Human Factors Involved in Organization of Staff and Personnel Management Procedures." In Knowledge and Skill in Working with Others What Makes a Good Public School? (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - 1954, "Brief Statement on Evaluation and the Construction of Examinations." In The Teaching of Physiology, Biochemistry, Pharmacology (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - 1954, Fact-Finding Study of the Testing Program of the United States Armed Forces Institute (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - 1954, Foreword to The Learner in Education for the Professions as Seen in Education for Social Work "Objective-Type Tests; Possibilities and Limitations for Graduate Schools." In The New England Conference on Graduate Education The Teacher Crisis (Box 61, Folder 9)
    - 1955, Foreword to Curriculum Study in Basic Nursing Education (Box 61, Folder 10)
    - 1955, Analysis of the Purpose, Pattern, Scope, and Structure of the Officer Education Program of Air University (Box 61, Folder 11)
    - 1956, "Clarifying the Role of the Elementary School." In Education, 2000 A.D. Evaluation in Relation to Problem Solving." In Science Teaching Through Problem Solving "Making the Most of a Scare Resource." In Expanding Resources for College Teaching (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - 1957, "The Curriculum; Then and Now." In Proceedings of the 1956 Invitational Conference on Testing Problems "Educational Values of Cooperative Education." In Highlights of the Conference on Cooperative Education and the Impending Educational Crisis (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - 1957, "Environmental Conditions for Effective Learning Through Problem-Solving." In Proceedings of the Summer Conferences and Institute "Evaluation of Learning Through Problem-Solving." In Proceedings of the Summer Conferences and Institute "Inter-Communication for Effective Learning Through Problem-Solving." In Proceedings of the Summer Conferences and Institute Facts About Practical Nurse Education in Michigan "Organizing a State Extension Research Program." In Organizing for Using Research in Extension "Scholarship and Education for the Professions." In Education for Social Work "Summary of Answers to Work Group Questions on Organizing a State Extension Research Program." In Organizing for Using Research in Extension "Ways of Getting Findings from Extension and Other Social Science Research Used." In Organizing for Using Research in Extension "What Will Be the Emerging Curricular Implications for Colleges and Universities of the New Social and Technological Concepts?" In Higher Education; A Bold New Look at the Not-Too-Distant Future (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - 1958, "Changing Horizons in Nursing Education." In New Dimensions of Learning in a Free Society "Curriculum Organization." In The Integration of Educational Experiences "The Education of Teachers; A Major Responsibility of Colleges and Universities." In The Education of Teachers; New Perspectives "Essential Aspects of Evaluation; What Is Evaluation?" In Evaluation of Reading "The Evaluation of Teaching." In The Two Ends of the Log; Learning and Teaching in Today’s College "Insights from the Behavioral Sciences." In Faculty-Administration Relationships "New Criteria for Curriculum Content and Method." In The High School in a New Era Foreword to An Experience in Basic Nursing Education "Recent Developments in Psychology and Their Application to Problems of Higher Education; Panel Discussion." In The Carnegie Conference on Higher Education (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - 1959, "Background for Recent Curriculum Developments." In Measurement Implications of Recent Curriculum Developments "A Behavioral Scientist Looks at Medicine." In Report of the First Institute on Clinical Teaching Institutional Organization of the Behavioral Sciences Introduction to Objectives of the Social Work Curriculum. Vol. 1; The Comprehensive Report of the Curriculum Study Review of "College Entrance Examination Board Achievement Test in Social Studies." In The Fifth Mental Measurements Yearbook Review of "Sequential Tests of Educational Progress; Social Studies." In The Fifth Mental Measurements Yearbook "The School Librarian's Boss." In The Climate of Book Selection; Social Influences on School and Public Libraries "Science and Education in Today's World." In Report of National Conference on Science in 4-H Club Work "Some Thoughts on Extension's Programs in the Years Ahead." In Report of National Conference on Science in 4-H Club Work (Box 62, Folder 5)